Ladies and gentlemen please welcome such a dialogue.
Good morning everyone and welcome to build twenty fifty.
It's exciting to be here ...build that in san francisco.
In fact I was just recounting I've been at every developer conference of
ours since nineteen ninety one in fact the very first one as a
third-party developer and after that as an employee at microsoft and
...just awesome to be here.
I know there is ...fantastic show lined up for you we have lots of things to talk about
in today's keynote one of the rest of the conference lots of things to show
you lots of announcements ...many new things but,
I think are going to be very exciting in terms of what
you will make of them in day one and what you will do on day two and thereafter?
For me in some sense.
...conference.
Is all?
About celebrating.
And, challenging.
The creativity in the in ...
Study you all ...
To build.
New great things on top of
platform innovations that we make available to you.
And, that.
Phenomenon is not new.
In fact it goes back to the very origin of our company.
Microsoft was founded by two developers.
Who had a bold ambition to empower other
developers to build new great thanks?
In fact ...you see on the screen.
Is the tree from paul allen on
our fortieth anniversary we turn forty in april?
And, these are the first lines of code.
Of ...bill and paul wrote it turns out that bill
rolled the run-time and paul wrote everything else and
...nice comment about we should put better errors so, it started in the very beginning.
When you look at it that?
...costs.
Laws changed in the forty years in a lot of technologies of
calm lot of technologies of gone in fact the very first
basic interpreter was written on a PP ten with an eighty,
eighty emulator that was built so that you could target the al
tear micro computer.
And, in the forty years a lot of devices of common gone a lot of technologies of
come and gone as they should.
What ...remained constant is that ethos?
That core than we ...
...company and a platform company first it is our mission
to empower every person an organization on the planet to
achieve more and when we talk about empowering every person
it starts by empowering every developer on the planet?
What you ...hear us talk about in this conference and even in this
morning's keynote is perhaps the broadest lens through which we
viewed developers development and platforms?
We're going to want developers from student developers to start ops
...enterprise developers to ISV to people writing mobile
...people venturing into virtual reality in mixed reality
all of these developers to calm exploit take advantage of
the platform innovation that you will see this morning and throughout this conference.
Want to make sure that we build bridges
...we want you to be able to bring your
skills your technology choices your languages
to our platforms and then build from there new and great
thinks.
Concept of that approach.
Is something that's going to
be deeply ingrained in everything we do across all of our platforms?
Over the last year I've had a chance to talk to many developers.
Throughout the world.
I met a couple student developers student developers who won the imagine
crop last year from australia labeled
...fantastic mobile app.
That it made it possible.
For you to be able to detect.
Anemia and children by just using a simple
lap and taking a ...and that at now is
changing lives in africa and other developing parts of the world.
I had a chance to meet a middle school or in the wrong single who
built a robot that could walk the stairs
in our eyes I could see that was just the very beginning of what she's going to do.
I have a chance to meet the enterprise developers in germany working in an
industrial equipment manufacturer and
they will fundamentally changing transforming the
business to becoming a software company as fast company.
So, I thought that is perhaps appropriate.
To kick-off billed.
By talking to one such developer.
In fact he's a musician.
Who had a dream?
And, the columns of
...accidental developer who had a dream.
To change.
How music is composed?
Please help me welcome david william ...
Hi, david my great senior great to be ...thanks for coming
...why do you tell us a little bit about your dream your journey so far
absolutely so music notation is probably something that a lot of you in this room
haven't really thought about before but it really is the written language of music it's almost like a
coding language of music actually in fact it has some similarities with code you can even
...and CSharp or upshot of shops probably better for that very.
...until now there's been two main ways you can really write music
traditionally using pattern paper which is very creative maybe not that
convenience sometimes or the digital way which is very laborious
through input but very convenient once it's in that form so I really wanted to make something where you
could take the creativity and the convenience and
smashing together and create this brand new way of writing music amazing do you want to show us what you
built absolutely ...stuff that is handwriting recognition for ...notation.
But, I've actually been working on a piece the last few weeks.
A piece of string quartet and piano.
And, as you can see I can use touch to interact with the school you can see we've got a
big school here this is note nursery rhyme.
And, let's go to the end we got a couple of bus left to do so I figured we could finish it up on stage
...sure your doctor music electric but go ahead how ...the company.
Ok, let's just take the pen I'm going to start writing in the bars
so it's very natural the idea behind the app was that if you could write music should be able to a?
Here if you can write music you should be able to know-how to use the app you don't need to really learn too much
...very intuitive as I move into the next bar.
Music notation is recognized intended to
...thank you moi.
But, actually this is actually interactive notation now so I can ...to cut it up.
And, maybe I should slur some of these two.
You think swimming's play like you drunk okay I'm getting so much trouble ...
Using touch I can double ...the bar select the bar and just pull this out
this is a great thing about surface and windows was really the only platform that we could do this for because it really
understands the difference between my fingers and the pen and that key that's really key to
making this into to the natural I'm just going to say this last beat ...that using the ...
And, I'm going to draw in a string run here.
And, pull that up and you can see that we've got a nice flash ...up to the top
so let me just to one less thing double type copy this down.
That's cool.
So, ...on that.
...and, we can play this back.
They go towards the ...of offset.
What's ...the reaction I know that this has been out for a few months is
...now ...just a few weeks and weeks on the ...is already been absolutely incredible
breathtaking really we've heard from people all over the world we have an eleven-year-old composer
he's writing her second up-front on the app model first second
and ninety one-year-old ...back in love with writing music and it's really been this students
using the classroom to classroom and it's really just an incredible reaction has been
...also thank you so much to me ...lot.
That's what's most striking about today's developers and all of you
which is one person or a small group of people with ...dream
and a passion can have such huge impact.
By taking advantage of these platform technologies who have thought that music
composition can be changed with touch in ink and that's what we live
for as a platform company we want to be able to take inspiration from the apps
you build drive platform innovation so today's keynote
is about three major platform transformations and
shifts.
We want to talk about first.
Our cloud platform.
We aspire to build.
An intelligent cloud back-end for the world's
applications running on all devices we want to have.
The capability to manage
infrastructures spanning datacenters so that means storage ...
...the network that's not just
about a datacenter as a computer but all of the data centers coming
together in support of these intelligent applications we want to have
rich applications services input particular data services such
as machine learning and democratize the taxes to those capabilities so
that every developer on every platform can build intelligent apps.
Second we want to talk about office as a platform.
We want to move far beyond.
Individual applications and their API.
To building ...rich.
Graph of data as a platform.
We want you to be able to consume that graph extend that
graph.
And, we'll talk a lot about that.
We want to talk about windows.
Windows ten.
Represents a new generation of windows built.
For an era of more personal computing from rats very
to the holographic computer where the mobility of
the experience is what matters not the mobility of the device.
Sort of kick things off let me have scott got three come up
...stage and talk about cloud platform thank you very much.
Thank you good morning everyone and welcome to built.
So, ...you just talk about our three core envisions as a company I'm
now going to continue the conversation and talk about the work we're doing to build
intelligent clout this is a broad ambition that spans a wide range of cloud services
at microsoft including office three sixty five and dynamics.
Today I'm going to talk about the work we're doing to
...our this ambition using as your.
As ...is microsoft's cloud computing platform enables you to
move faster and do more ...hyper scale club platform in over the last
several years we've built out asher to run all over the world?
The circles on this map indicate agile regions which are made up of clusters
of data centers where you can run deploy your code.
Today we have nineteen unique as a regions open for
business that's more locations and more countries ...both of us and the google
cloud combined and this enables you to run your applications closer to your customers and employees
than ever before and compete and even more geographic markets.
We continue to invest billions of dollars each year building out new infrastructure that
...cloud platform now manages more than one million servers.
This enables you to build apps without having to worry about your
club platforms capacity enables you to scale your solutions to any size.
...offers the choice and flexibility of a full spectrum clap.
Enables you to build apps that scale from personal projects optical
global scale applications you can start from scratch for new greenfield
perhaps we can easily leverage your existing investments and skills.
It's ...the ability to target
multiple devices use multiple operating systems programming languages frameworks
...data services and tools we allow you to put all of your app announcer
...support hybrid deployments expand on premises for ...
You can choose to use ...just for infrastructure just use it for base compute storage
...networking you could also take advantage of coherent set of highly
engineered services to build your apps even faster
...our cloud platform and tools combination together deliver on
match productivity enable you to move faster and be even more successful
so busy twelve months for the ads are team since our last build conference a year ago
we deliver more than five hundred new asher services and features in that time
...greatly expanded the footprint in capabilities of what out your delivers
and, what we're seeing is as we're kind of ...our features as we've expanded our footprint around the
world we're seeing the usage of asher continue to rapidly growth we have more than ninety thousand new
...customer subscriptions now being created every month
...those customers are creating some really amazing applications more than one-point-four
million sequel databases are now being used by applications hosted inside out your way
more than fifty trillion objects now stored in the hash restored system?
Four hundred twenty five million users interact
...directory system three million developers ...with our visual studio online
services are online suite of developer sas offerings
...seeing the growth ...happen not just in the enterprise and business user space
but, more than forty percent over as your revenue and usage now comes actually from startups
...for my speech behind these large momentum numbers are some truly amazing customer
...the slide contain some of the logos are just a few of the
company's doing great things and asher and throughout today's keynote
...hear me talk more about some of their specific stories and some of the reasons why they're using ...
...of these we know is that a cloud platform must offer the flexibility of choice
...enables you to use the best of the windows ecosystem
and the best of the linux ecosystem together as your ...easily reuse the skills
you already have regardless of the programming languages you use ...
to take advantage of both core infrastructure capabilities and higher-level platform services
and microsoft unique ...that it's the only hyper scale cloud provider that architects
those higher-level services and program model capabilities to run multiple environments including
build on premises data centers that you already have as well as other clouds besides our own.
From the beginning of ...even braced open-source
in a very deep way and over this past year in particular we've taken a number
of significant steps to use open-source even more broadly last year we
announced plans to deeply embrace darker and darker ecosystem
...as you're in windows server and make containers
of fundamental part of our application platform.
Will also open-source our core dot net runtime technology an announcer plans
supported on multiple platforms ...rules obviously make it first-class when running
within containers and this combination is really powerful enables even more developer flexibility and
choice?
We'd like to do kick things off is actually invite the ...globe and markers ...
...here to talk about this work and show off pretty cool demo
...action here's bent.
Thank you scott.
So, for those of you who are not aware doctor has just celebrated its second birthday so, freely
we're used to thinking of ...kind of like human two-year-old, you know, occasionally stumbles occasionally
spits up and keeps those of us who are closest to it up at night and, ...of surprising to be up here
on stage it failed in fact I talk about the five big surprises that we've had in working with
microsoft at all or ...ways relate to this notion of how we can take openness
and portability and flexibility and use it to empower developers now if you're not familiar with
...started two years ago by solomon
hikes who felt that developers fundamentally are spending far too much of their time.
Doing rework worrying about dependencies worrying about servers instead of just building
awesome maps and initial innovation was let's make it possible to
take any application and it's dependencies package them up in the digital equivalent of
a shipping container enable any application that stock rise to interact with any other
...rise application and run any server ...october when we
went up to meet with microsoft we're very proud of the fact we got networking for linux
you could take any linux application doc ...run it on any linux server and quite frankly we
saw we leaves redmond with an agreement to make soccer for linux run well on hyper
...or run well in manager but then we have the first of those big five surprises and
the first big surprise was that we were not going to work on doctor for linux we're going to work on
doctor for windows so we're going to enable the four million
doctor linux developers to join all the millions
...developers and make it possible using standard darker
using open-source to take any windows application doc
...and run it on any server second great surprise that we had was this is not only
about code was also about content collaboration you're familiar with doctor, you know,
we have a service called doctor hub that has about a ...twenty thousand doc rise gaps.
Microsoft has not only integrated darker ...into all of
its developer platforms but is contributing actively to doctor hub not just
...windows components but all of these great new open-source dot net for
linux components delivered again is doctor containers to the hub.
Third great surprise that we had was at microsoft embrace the notion of what you need to do to
make multi container apps work and embrace the notion if you want to make multi container
actually portable you have to be open about how you do orchestration as well so
were so thrilled that microsoft has embraced dockers open orchestration initiatives compose machine
it's warm fourth-grade surprising yes, there's more combine those three things.
You're not only going to be able to
make great multi container windows applications are great multi container windows
applications you'll be able to mix and match windows containers and
...containers which means you'll be able to use ...linux back-end and windows front-end
or vice versa basically choose the best damn tools for the best damn application
that you want to build and run it on any server.
And, the fifth and perhaps greater surprise we've had working with microsoft is ...
...happen quickly and everything that I've spoken about is either live
or working well in the lab right now so without further ado I'd like to bring a microsoft which city of
...on board to show you what happens when you combine these great platforms together again
...our developers.
Mark I love the ...thank you richard
...everybody right so what I've got right in front of you here is an
...dot net five application fabric cameras and e-commerce site
...of a standard ...I'm going to be doing some dev test
on the first thing I'd like to do is to deploy it to a doctor container running ...
windows server machine on this step test box I've got a virtual machines running windows server with doctor support
doctor container support and I'm going to take a look at the containers that I've already got running in
a virtual machine ...executing the darker ps command which
lists the active containers you can see
I've got two containers active one is a mine crafts server and the other one is no,
JS application which shows that
doctor containers on windows support many different run times in languages that you might be using.
Now what I'm going to do is package up the fabric cam applications that I can also deployed into container and I'm
going to use a several doctor commands here one called doctor build which
we'll package it up ...the image that's produced with the name fabric
camp so it's easy to remember.
And, then go ahead and package that ...going to be executing a series of steps
which take that ASP dot net five application package it up in a
...to image and the next step.
Is to run that container with that image
so I'll type darker run dash IT to make it interactive you'll see
why I'm doing this in a second and?
Forget the documents darker.
Run and fabric ...
Now the reason that I've had it be
...so that we can print-out the IP address so I can see the IP address of the website that's
going to launch that fabric an application if I go back and
do a darker ps at this point you'll see that fabric
came image has been launched into a container here now one of the really fun parts
about using the doctor client is that if you don't specify name for your container it comes up with
a random one so let's go see what names ...come up with it called this one tender
and look at that but that's what are the odds of that coming up like that?
So, let's take a look at that website now which is going to be active launch
IEEE the IP addresses ten fifty dot zero ...one twenty two and we're hitting tend
...fifty.
That one zero two and then we go net running
...windows server container executed with darker but I'm showing you a lot of
technologies ...might not be familiar with so just a quick raising and how many people have heard of linux?
Okay, for those people and they're watching a lot about a third of the audience raise your hands.
I'm just getting everybody raise their hand of course.
But, what I'm ...to show you is scott mention that we've got dot net support on linux and we
integrate it with doctor containers as well so here I've got the
same exact application and this time I'm going to sh into a
linux virtual machine and run the doctor ps ...can see I've got no containers running
in that virtual machine instead of using darker run to ...right
...visual studio using the public command?
Right here I've configured to launch
to that darker host here's the IP address that host when I type publish press
publish here it's going to package it up and execute the same doctor klein commands
to deploy that fabric came application on to linux if I go back and type
doctor ps again you'll see there's fabric
can latest and there's the name prickly was knack always fun to look at the
...of the doctors ...creates.
Let's go see if that websites come up and sure enough there it is and you can see that that's
the same IP addresses this h command so I'm looking at the
darker container running on that virtual machine.
But, now there's more I'm doing ...test of this fabric
...application and I'd like to continue to use
visual studio to do that and I can now with integration of container debugging
into visual studio somebody got a server explore got a virtual machines there's
the doctor VM and there's a prickly was knack container I attach the butter.
just as a normal visual studio debugging experience I've got the libraries loaded here and you can
...sure enough there's the core CLR
for linux underneath this application that I've just attached to.
And, I want to sort of break point here on the function that I'm debugging I go back
to the website it refresh and I'm at the break point debugging.
Net in linux deployed in
the doctor content thank you very much.
So, we've been developing the cross platform version of the dot
...core one-time in the open on get out the last several months and
...today the announcer also releasing now preview addition of the runtime in pre
compiled binary format that you can download and start using for
...for linux as well as for mac.
That's incredibly exciting time in the world today
disruption is changing economy in a fundamental way not
just in technology but in traditional service industries as well ...
...have predicted that both the taxi and the hospitality business
...been turned upside down five years ago ...companies like
...were in error B and B are doing just that every organization is looking for ways to
engage customers better empower their employees more and ultimately transform
the value they deliver and developers and the applications and solutions that they
build played absolutely integral role in enabling us in fact
increasingly digital
laps and technology that enable businesses to delight their customers
and differentiate from one another and it's never been a better time I think right now than to be to be a developer.
Badger enables you to invoices transformation and,
make you and your teams even more successful without ...we deliver a rich set ...higher-level
services that provide fully engineered solutions that enable you to move faster
...achieve more and the combination of our cloud platform and tools really delivers
unparalleled developer productivity as you do this ...is a customer of I
think provides an excellent example of what ...your productivity can really deliver a three and four
...companies in the world eighty, eighty eight thousand employees
and little deliver tens of thousands of products and three-M is using
...to build the back-end for many of these products ...they love the agility
that as your provides them to move quickly and deliver even more value and what the initial projects
they hosted on manager was an internal mobile ...that they wanted to provide
their sales force to sell a new offering that they just actually come out with and
a small roman team that actually never used out your before signed up on a friday
and basically spent the weekend building the app and had by the end we can have a fully production
ready version deployed on as you're ready to roll up their sales force on monday and
this ability to quickly create robust enterprise ready applications with
super-fast development cycles ...really provided three-M with incredible business agility and helps
...even faster as an overall organization ...of the great productivity solutions as
...delivers is our asher app service
this is a really powerful offering that we released just last month and provides a
sweetie capabilities that enable you to quickly build in scale both web
...mobile applications anywhere in the world?
Have service allows you to write back encode logic using dot net java
no gs ...and python it you can easily
...continuous integration workflows to it from online
source repository like visual studio online get hub in bit bucket and that enables it so
that every time a developer checks encode into one of those services as
you can automatically building tested deployed to a private production slot and
everything's looking good and basically turned on the production and
...for monitoring analytics on top of it?
Using actors built in
...capability you can set of rules so once you deploy the application your application
can automatically scale-up based on incoming traffic in fact you get a massive
influx of traffic you can basically set up a huge number of instances and handle basically any amount
...and when you're traffic drops as you can basically automatically shut down those
resources to help you save money and pay only for what you actually need?
Couple features we've added recently to the as rap service is enterprise connectivity and
this allows you the ability to set up a virtual private networks that allows you to connect back to
...on premise enterprise network and axes apps ...data that you wish to make available in the
cloud ...really easy to integrate with existing enterprise solutions you already have
and address service also now provide
support for easily integrating data and functionality from popular sas solutions like
...sixty-five dynamics and sales force and you can use the logic
gaps functionality within
...service to create long-running workflows to automate business processes.
...like to do is invites got handsome here on
...to show off ...as rap service and what you can build with ...
Hi, friends.
You know, we're really excited about the maker movement and things like raspberry pies and three-D
printers
...pick up one of these are great and one of the applications that we brought here the fabric
...application is a makers space and they sell things like printer
...three-D printers and net we know why files and things like that but they also offer a
service ...I can go and upload a three-D print I've got a
three-D object here and three-D builder that you can go and get up on the windows store ...
...him into this application that is running in as your
app ...we bring him up and then hit
upload this modern application area you've got actually got a little javascript three JS
there showing me the model that tell me where I can pick it up and
when and this is now going to go through a process it's talking to a back-end
order service the one that we saw and let's switch
over into visual studio and see how we built that now this
is that ASP dot net five application using the dot net course she'll are and,
using modern techniques that is talking to the back-end this order details
back-end is running within the context of asher and we're using a
channel five ...three all the kinds of modern things that you'd expect and
we're actually bringing in our and pm inside
of visual studio and because I'm a web developer I want to use my
web development skills to make other applications so we also have
the back-end for the administrator so when someone at the store
gets that three-D print we can click on the order they've got access to that print so
they're using this application on a surface to talk to the same order
...pie that the website does we've got built into visual studio tools for
apache cordova that are also using html and javascript and
we're reusing some of that javascript as well and I can go and generate
mobile applications I could certainly use CPlus-plus or tools like salmon in this case tools for
...cordova have allowed me to create a mobile
lab so I can go and make purchases from the store and also check on my
order you maybe have seen the windows emulator that runs on hyper
V that comes with visual studio but you may not be familiar with
...and write ...this is an andrea emulator that comes with visual studio
you have this and I can go and check on my order from that and
write emulator running under hyper V at full speed all part of the apache
...tools that are built in here ...also includes debugging and
a really amazing experience for people making mobile applications on any platform let's switch over
to visual studio online and see our managing this code now in this
case our team is working on it get repository that's running in
visual studio online you can see john callaway is making some?
Changes here but not only are we doing source control within via so but
we're also managing our backlog so we can keep track of what's working and what's
not working in this con bon war we've got full support for work items but more interestingly
to me is that workflow that the team is going through we've got the
...running in visual studio online as well so this ASP dot net five net course
...is building in via and then deploying out to the applications
and as rapture
this automatically now if I switch over to measure I can see
that application in the API host here and when I move
that into production we can click within as your itself and see the deployments
here as well so I can see a deployment that john put out on sunday
click on that and that integration with visual studio online I can see his
commits whether that build succeeded so I check into get visual studio
online it runs the build runs the test make sure that everything is okay sends it
out into asher once it's in a measure in production I can also scale
it can automatically scale it coming here and scale by I can set the
number of instances and a target range of the sheep views of the cpu goes above
a certain amount the application will scale so I get the full
lifecycle from visual studio all up through
production and now this application in production scaling I want to
get insights into what's going on and you would expect to have great web insights
we've got application insight showing is all sorts of details we have dependency
tracking all the way down to a single line of code so from visual studio and as
you've got the best dev ops that allow teams to create both web and mobile
laps with our recent integration of hockey app I've got the same deep
insights for mobile applications so inside integrated into
manager you can see here the mobile app crashes events
sessions by country I can go all the way down to a single line of code and here's actually the
...version of this application and I can go and see specifically what
worked what didn't down to an exact line in this case of swift code
such as three hundred sixty degree view
of any platform from the highest level all the way down to the
lowest-level to a single line of code so this is a lot to take
...let's step back for a second and get an understanding about how this fits
...we've got web apps we've got mobile applications
those are talking to API and the back-end when I submitted my order
it went to this order API written ...net ...
Those API asking be written by me or they can be written by third-party or brought in
from our marketplace but a really interesting thing is this concept of logic
applications because there's business processes like when that order gets completed I want to get
notified as a customer about that so let's take a look at what a logic application.
Let me switch over here we go so this is an application here where
we've got individual API apps the sequel connector is going
to be looking at the data for the orders and then it flows through this work
flow from one API up to another using a technology called swagger where that
meta data is going to the system into sales force and then in this case
we're posting a message to slack I can bring in that
order API that we created an asp dot net and then get the details
for that order you see that actually got populated using that swagger details and
then it knows about previous things within this ...this
is a reliable durable workflow in the cloud and now I can click on truly
oil and bringing that's really a connector and then send a message
to let-me know when this when this order is completed.
So, here I can access any aspects of what ...flowing
through the system in this case I'll look at the phone number
and we will have the from number VTwo number.
And, then under text here we're going to have.
Hi, person sales force first name your order
is reading this is the kind of common business process that you don't necessarily want to write
...because it changes a lot and this is all happening in the cloud
in this business orchestration service called logic
apps and you can integrate this with any
existing application running on any language not just dot net node python anything that create
...that can create a swagger application can do this now.
I think this is pretty amazing but I feel like perhaps I haven't sufficiently
blow your mind and I promised a number of people that I would do that so let's take a moment and then
switch over to our
macintosh here now on this mac you can see that I can load up visual studio
online I can manage my code and write my cross platform dot
net applications I can do that using any one of the many editors that one
would use a mac like e-max sublime and things like that but inevitably I find myself going into
spotlight on a mac and just wishing that there was a member of the visual studio family that I can somehow run.
I'm really, really happy to announce that visual studio code.
This is a code optimized development tool that runs natively on windows
mac and linux it supports dozens of languages out-of-the-box it's ...
Application for all kinds of things that you're going to do that
are code focused but it's not just
a simple editor it has deep insight into what's going on this is the same fabric
ham order details application here is ...code peak I can
see the references are go and go into order details.
From here I can hover over individual objects
get information about them and help and I get real intel
us sense not just auto complete in this case powered by
the open-source tools of roslyn and on a sharp.
So, this is pretty freaking amazing I can also.
Do things like this will bring in a little refactoring here
make a change say this and I've got get?
And, gifts and I can push it visual studio online
...where will then run through the process be built tested deployed and scaled
to asher which is pretty fantastic visual studio code but,
this is still not really blowing my mind I feel I could do
even better so why don't we take a moment and switch over to move on to?
So, now I'm in my application in this case I'm using
a mono application big thanks to the folks at mono help to help us with mono
four-point-one that this demo is running on I can now click on debug.
Launch an interactive debugging session so now I'm on a
...to it dot net app doing a debug session I've got
local variables I've got a call stack I've got break points all in this great
lightweight code editor visual studio code this I think
makes the point that visual studio is now if family of tools for
every developer and asher is the cloud back-end for
everyone.
And, I just got a text message on my band that my three-D print is
being delivered how nice thank you I now those that's great now my scott you action figure
as a ...a cell ...
Well, thank scott those kind of agree example the type of
...in productivity the combination of as you're
...visual studio family now provides you can seek as
howard mentioned earlier three sixty degree view from coding to deployment to testing to
source control management to running in scaling your application does at all you also
volunteers saw our news addition to the visual studio family which is visual studio
code visual studio code is a code optimize editing
...it's small fast and provides both coding ...
sense and debugging support as you saw is for integration forget and one of
things were ...on windows on mac as well as
...development machines and really
excited to announce the remaking available for free.
And, even better we're pleased to announce later
today the first download of it will be made available on all those platforms for you to start using.
Our mission with visual studio is to provide best in class tools for every
developer and we now have tools for developers who like lightweight code optimize
elders as well as for those looking for a full development enterprise id.
And, with visual studio online ...scott showed we now provide a full sweep of
developer services that run in the cloud that delivery full application lifecycle management
experience including source control plug-in work item tracking continuous integration
...testing performance crash analytics and a whole bunch more what
grades you can take advantage of all these services directly from any of our visual studio development tools
where you can also use them for many other development tool as well
...this really enables you to build amazing applications
in this mobile first cloud first-world ever really excited to talk more about this in the
breakout talks and all the great features that are coming in visual studio this year.
The mortgage
recent roller famous article few years ago we talk about how software is eating the world
and about how companies will increasingly deliver value through online services
today more than ninety percent of all technology companies are now delivering
or building online sas services to deliver more about value
and better connect with customers and many of our biggest customers using
actor today are using it to build and deliver sas services
to their customers this includes both born in the cloud companies as well
as enterprises that are reinventing themselves by becoming technology firms.
Ask you whether it is a great example of one of those companies
the one the largest weather forecasting services in the
world the originally actually eight of us customer and switched asher to our
weather service they process more than six billion data requests each day through the rate
...for temperature and weather forecasts and they use
asher for weather prediction as well as the our all of their iowa us ...
windows out doc you signs another great example they provide electronic signature signing
...service ...growing at three hundred percent year over year for seven years now
...now service more than one hundred twenty thousand enterprise customers
are fantastic example of a successful startups
...valuation is now worth billions.
...healthcare is working to provide their customers
...doctors and hospitals easier ways to collect
...report healthcare data ...deployed multiple sat applications on out
...all meeting the most stringent regulatory environments
this we could build we're going to talk about a number of new technologies that we're delivering ...
...you to build great high scale
sat services like these one of the technologies ...talk about is something we call
...service ...service fabric is the high control distributed computing
framework we created ...our own high scale cloud services and we
battle hardened it over the last several years under extreme loads and then
super demanding requirements it supports the ability to create cloud services composer both speak
...and statefull micro services
and has support for hyper scale out deployments self healing
...management as walls orchestration of code updates and
release the service fabric SDK make available on both windows as well as linux
systems the first downloaded that will be available this week and in addition
to supporting actor you also be able to use it to build great solutions that run in a multi cloud
...we have a great
...later today ...going to more detail on it?
Now do you think about building great sas applications one of the things that sort of
fundamental building goes is to be able to do great data management
...supports a wide variety of data storage and management solutions you
...use pretty much every commercial or open-source data management offering on asher
and microsoft also optimizes and delivers both relational and
no sequel data solutions as highly available managed services that you can basically
deploying use
our sequel database offering is one of our most popular offerings it's a cloud native
...a service is highly available durable and fault tolerance
enables you to store and manage data without having to worry about infrastructure
patching software updates for backups that's all built in as part of the service you can
provision ...sequel database in just seconds and run it literally anywhere around the world and you
can set up a sequel database ...geo replicate transactions across multiple as
your regions while you're doing enabling automatic fail over support
within your applications as well as geographic scale-up we've got some great new features
the sequel databases over the last few months like elastic scale support which enables you to
shards scale ...sequel database is three petabytes in size and in memory
...support which gives you ...hundred X performance improvements for many
core data scenarios ...because again single databases offered as a
managed service as opposed to just ...database inside of the
...developers are able to host scale and use databases and a true cloud native way in
fact up to a hundred sixty thousand sequel databases ...crop created or
dropped every single-day using ...for a wide variety different scenarios
...I do is actually just talk about joe nice video of one of the customers ...sequel database
actually over ten thousand sequel database is running on asher today this is as
...who's leading provider of geographic information services
...video talk about how to take advantage of?
My name's as the chief technology officer location ...history has been
in microsoft measure march from the very beginning days and we've ...a ...
...aren't just online using microsoft ...has re-use as your sequel
database geo enabled this data of our users with mapping analytic ...
...that's out there ...take advantage of this few companies public safety whatever
maybe ...scenarios like government needs to
be semi-public data in response to a natural disaster people want to know what ...
...extraordinary effort to get fresh water and food but when they make these maps data
available ...sometimes it goes viral when that happens we have to be able to scale
a moment's notice enough gases that platform we can do?
Working on things that actually make a difference in people's ...that means.
...to announce today a number of great new enhancements tour sequel database
...that you can start using immediately these include
tv support which provides the ability for you to
ensure and control encryption at rest policies within your databases full-text
search support which enables you to run text queries against your data a new capability
...particular excited about ...lasting
database pool which enables you to better manage lots of databases even
lower-cost is perfect for the solutions
...challenges for developers that are building
sas space applications that serve lots of BB customers is
...for the right data model one approaches to use a
shared database where you have lots of customers sharing the same tables of
data this is a this is good from a resource cost perspective but introduces
high operational quote complexity ...your application now another approach that many sas perhaps
...to maintain a separate database per B to be customer
...provides great data isolation ...that
node two companies data is ever stored in the same database but in the passes typically more
expensive since each database uses a separate set of resources
...were really excited to introduce our new elastic database pool support which gives you the
best of both worlds ...elastic database pool all enables you to maintain
completely isolated databases for each of your B to be customers but,
then allows you to aggregate all the resources necessary to run those resources
are databases into a common resource pool and this allows you to smooth out the peaks and
dips of different databases within your sat out ...end up using
for fewer resources to run your application and the end result is that it saves
you lots of money also improving the overall operational complexity of running
...solution what to do is invite lore on ...show those often action?
...walk through some great new updates with as
your sequel database and sas developers are going to love this stuff.
As status talked about you can let as your dynamically
manage your database resources using elastic database pool.
And, the best part is this could also save you money when you first create a cool one of the decisions
...to make is what databases should you even put in the
We've removed a lot of this guesswork.
We're using machine learning behind the scenes to produce a list of recommended
databases to go into a pool we're going to take that list of databases and we'll just adam.
want these databases to dynamically use a pool of resources.
So, we have
these visualizations that help us properly size what that pool should look like.
Based on the databases that we selected.
But, what's also very important is that you can
specify the minimum and maximum performance characteristics of all
of your databases and basically what this means is any
database can have a spike and performance but they're not going
to end up being a noisy neighbor to any of the other databases in the pool.
Now you don't have to worry about what size you're going to give your
database us as zero a three SOne.
Just let ...dynamically figure that out for you you're going to have the best cost
fear company you get the best application performance your customers.
Let's go through some developer stuff.
We have this reports and this is a report for the fabric him
companies and the it allows franchise owners to see how their stores are
performing.
The really cool thing about this report is that it's a
...live data from all
of the databases in our cool we had thirty
databases and it's using a single connection string and the single query.
a few weeks we're going to deliver in preview elastic database query.
And, creating a report with a
single connection string against a group of databases will be as simple as ...star.
And, finally how do you manage updates and changes when you're in
a sas world you have tens hundreds of thousands
of databases how do you make updates to all of those databases,
for example, with our world we may want to restrict the
rows of data so that each franchise owner only sees the data
to the stores that they don't well.
Answer ...database delivered role level security sometime ago we want to
implement that but that's going to require a change to all of our databases.
To make any database chains.
Any ...maybe you want to do a maintenance update
we'll use the new elastic database job.
We'll take our standard
...call that we know and love and we're going to just submit this
...click correctly submit this as a job.
To our pool.
All colors are less for lower-level security so
...cyclic run my work is
...do all the rest of the work I don't have to write my
custom script that loops through all the databases I don't have to manage to
retry logic I don't have to think about how I'm going to scale this to
tens and hundreds and thousands of databases answer takes
care of all of that for me I can use this for maintenance jobs like rebuilding
indexes I can use this for other standard statistics updates
or just one-time updates any kind of update like that?
And, after this completes running.
It's already almost complete against all of our databases.
And, if we just give it a second and we refresher report hopefully
martina only sees the rows of data for the stores that she owns.
now you've got these fantastic new tools that will help really build robust
staff applications using as your sequel database thank you.
So, you see routing lots of great enhancements to our overall data
story in terms of enabling you to store operational
allies data whether it's in a single database or across thousands of them
...switch gears now and talk also now about how you can use analytics on top of that data what ...
unique world right now in terms of the expectations people have around intelligent apps
in companies that embrace analytics will be much more content competitive in this
...economy than those who don't your data
combine with analytics enables you to answer
business critical questions and build much better apps questions like what are the products with a
...already purchased something from you want what's the likelihood of a customer yours churning
where the warning signs you should watch out for before they do so what is
the price elasticity of your products and services how you optimize for that
...sufficient product availability for the upcoming holiday or for special
promotion being able to answer these questions accurately and use that
insight to improve your applications can transform your business now in the past
answer questions like this was painful data warehouses took months to set up
and integrating analytic systems heart.
But, as you're we now provide a suite of highly
engineered analytic services that make answering these types of questions easy
all enables you to basically maximize the value of each by the data that
your application stores and processes each of these services ...can be ...
minutes and compose together they provide complete full solutions.
today I'm excited to announce to new ...services that were launching the compliment
existing offering even further ...make it even easier to unlock insights from data.
Our new sequel database service makes it easy for anyone to set up a data warehouse
to aggregate in-store data ...just minutes ...scale the sequel data
...service to store petabytes of data independently scale compute to
match whatever resources you need to ...or doors offering makes it
easy to interactively query and visualize all the data stored within it as well as operational
eyes machine learning on top of it like to do ...show quick video of it action.
Imagine how could you make your business more intelligent ...data ...
...the digital customers using ...services come from how can you engage them better improve customer
With discounts affect your infantry much.
Imagine you could use data to analyze these questions and intelligently project that.
The feature question moi.
Most ...you have any of that but now you can use
...unlimited put you out your question.
Reducing sequel data ...the new sequel data
...services easy generate ...be launched a minute.
The industry's first typed data warehouse that can grow will shrink to any size and second.
Which you can use to intelligently on any question using thanks?
Easily encode data for any data
...data pipelines sequel moi exceed.
As well as on premise ...consistent and you can easily create reports against what is ...
...life simply connect microsoft ...I suggest that.
...to easy-to-use predicted ...and as you machine learning and now you
specified scale ...applications written on my thought is
analyzed customer product as.
Assessed customization race you can expose machine learning API that you're absent
...more intelligent interact with your customers.
The data warehouse ...can scale-up and second neighbors
...as your machine learning to tap into unlimited query our.
So, you can visualize and explore unlimited scenario.
The our to the state of the building ...never been greater.
Using our new sequel data warehouse
service you can easily stand-up and aggregate data from any source.
You can archive data from your operational sequel or no sequel database
...you also than aggregate that data from on premises data like SAP system
or a dynamic system you can also easily aggregate data from ...do cluster and,
be able to import any type of data from ...your data is in the data warehouse you can easily
visualize ...interact with it using our new our by service
that provides a rich way you can visualize your data and ask questions of it
...also run reports against as well as stand-up and, use
...machine learning to create predicted models on top of that data ...one of things that makes our machine learning
service so powerful is that once you create a
predictor model with it you can expose it as an API that you're apps can now
call and use and this basically means the more data you get the ...
and creates a virtual cycle ...really allows you to build some truly amazing systems.
The other data ...warehouse offerings in the market today ...
...idea is to see the good uplift with ...red shift offering for just a little bit of time
talking about how now as your is even better unlike red shift you can independently
adjust the amount of compute and, storage that you use with ...sequel data warehouse
this allows you to reduce costs and pay only for you actually need.
You can automatically scale-up ...
your data warehouse in seconds this is a big difference versus red shift
...typically takes hours or even days to reschedule your data warehouse ...your data
...goes into a read-only mode with perfect relation
...allows you to basically increase in decrease pretty much it will.
Richard doesn't have the ability to pause a cluster so,
unlike sequel data warehouse where you can pause when you no longer need your data
where else and pay only for storage this allows you to reduce costs and pay only for what
you actually need.
A great example of that might be when the end of the month ...the quarter you
needed data whereas you no longer needed just turn it off and you're having to pay for anything.
Our sequel data warehouse runs not just in as
you can also be deployed and run
it on premises environment unlike others of compatibility and features
that perspective sequel data where else provides a full sequel experience
it allows you to build super powerful applications with these four really excited about what
sequel data warehouse delivers we think is really
a perfect opportunity for you to build ...data in a really rich way
...every developer to get your insights from the data half.
...exciting opportunities fighting for every business out there is to use the internet of
things to transform how we build products and how they engage with customers and we have
some fascinating use cases of biotech solutions built now on as
your forties adding I'll t sensors to all of their
...to improve the overall car owner experience and they've built a ...
...back in solution on ...the ...process all this data ...
...connecting it with a customer information that they already store within apps they own inside their
own on premises datacenters and providing a full complete solution rockwell automation has partner
for the biggest energy super majors out there ...basically
now running unmanned internet connected gas dispensers each dispenser
...management information which they can basically then use machine learning on top of
to detect anomalies and predict one proactive,
proactive maintenance needs to be done on machines and my favorite examples probably
the nfl most teams the nfl now use the
xs knows thunder cloud platform for record analyze
share game and player data in your realtime during the game?
This funnel cloud solution runs on algebra and in addition to providing real-time statistics
...on place it also records
and codes and uploads video they can be used for ...game analysis
...walk through some of the canonical services you can use an as you're to build these types of
...back ends are using the as your event
...a service which released just last fall you can now in
...process tens of millions of bio team messages per second.
You can use the
...stream analytic service which we may generally available this month to perform near
real-time analytics on top of these
OT messages and you could operational allies it using a combination of our
by to create rich data visualization dashboard of the stream data.
You can awfully now store the raw data or more commonly a subset of the data inside
in these databases that we run inside algebra you can now
...on the raw data within our new data like service that
were making available announcing this week those new data like service that we're announcing today is really
a revolutionary way to store and process data we've built the new
data like service using more than a decade of real-world ...managing
...bytes of data for our own microsoft services and.
daily service enables you to store literally an infinite amount of data you can create accounts that store
exploits of content with individual files that are up to a petabyte in size.
And, this infinite capacity allows you to keep data in its original form whether
it's bioterror log files for any other non relational structure.
You can enron high throughput low latency analytic jobs to
analyze and process this data at any scale you don't have to worry about setting up or
managing your own clusters to do this instead you can focus on the task at hand
that you want to get accomplished and the service for automatically scale out for ...and,
apply the appropriate resources to get it done the service provides
built in enterprise great security support enabling ...securely locked down control
and access to any data you store within it ...agree things about the data like service is
that exposes data using the standard who do phd ...yacht.
And, this enables you actually leverage any analytic software already out there that
supports each ...is allows you, for example, run standard do jobs
...workloads on top of anything's stored inside the data
like you can take advantage of ...or applications using our new revolution
...distribution and be able now have those
scale out and query against literally ...of content you also stand-up and use
VM hosted cloud era as well as important works clusters
to access and run analytics stored inside the data like as well this gives you maximum
flexibility enables you to drive even more insight from the data that you ultimately store.
So, as are now has ...the richest analytic capabilities of any
clap enables you to build intelligent maps that are highly differentiate
for your customers and this morning I talk about some of these types of applications you can do with
...can use to drive your business disrupt businesses or grow profits.
This technology can also be used to really change the world in on business ways
as well and one of ...I like to do is invite on stage ...who's doing just that
and it's just giving you basically optimize philanthropic giving campaigns and,
help funnel money into good causes
...do is invite might become the onstage to talk about what they do and how they're doing it without her?
Great morning.
This is what I'm going to talk to you about today this is what we've built
on the platform we call it the give graph.
It's a set of complex algorithms that will fundamentally change the way you and I
interact with causes that we care about is going to change the way we give.
to give you some context let me tell you a little bit about our company first where based in the UK and
...the largest social given platform to enable people to raise money and
do amazing things for the causes and for the charities that they care about some people decide
to do the marathon obviously recently people were throwing buckets of cold water on top of
the head all in the name of charity and we've been fortunate in having around twenty
three million people from over a hundred and sixty countries in the world?
Do this and they've raised in excess of three billion dollars
for charity and for good causes and this is taken us a lot closer to our goal which is to
ensure that every great corps gets the funding that it requires now we live in a
world where we have billions of people who have that natural desire to give?
An if everyone did that we would eradicate poverty.
We would put cancer out of business now
...team had the task of trying to understand why that isn't happening using analytics
using machine learning and getting a real understanding as to how we think and how we make that decision
to give and our analytics has identified three key things that are product
needed to use data for the first is that it needed to change giving from being
a transactional activity to something that's far more engaging it also
need to be personal of course it needed to be social after all we
sold some of the biggest problems as human species by connecting with each
other and collaborating but at the heart of all of this is that we needed to
make giving personal which for us means we need to understand what
you specifically care about traditional ways of trying to address personalization we
would use things like look-alikes
or collaborative filtering but in this space that doesn't work what you care about
...specific to you if you care about cancer or beating cancer I can't
find somebody who looks like you and say that they also care about cancer everybody
has something specific that they care about however using machine learning and
graph theory on this platform we've managed to crack that problem
in fact what we've done is we've built a machine does that those three specific
things first of all it understands how you specifically want to give
giving isn't just about money it understands whether you want to give time or
whether you want to give effort secondly the algorithm can
work out specifically what you care about and it also understands that what you
care about changes it's a moving database it's not static it ...
as your circumstances change as your associations change and the more interactive you
become and, lastly my most favorite part of the algorithm is that it understands how
to interact with you specifically with you to make giving more engaging and remove
those barriers that might exist to stop you from giving now we couldn't have done
is without the as your platform where small team of scientists and engineers
and what is your platform really allowed us to do was focus intensely on our
goal we don't have a team of operations experts ...can managing huge cluster of ...
...cloud machines in the cloud but this platform was ideal for us and these are the
components that we used and this is how we architect them essentially had
three core processes we had a batch process which runs nightly a real-time
process and approaches that allowed us to put our API in front of the product?
And, the ...process is the backbone
for everything that we do and at the center of it is HD insight this is where we do all of
our large calculations this is where we build that give graph that I
showed you earlier so essentially we take all of our data we uploaded into blob storage
...spin up the clusters and do all of our calculations and once that's done the classes
...put down in the data is moved on to ...your table storage and that same time we have a
realtime service that helps us keep this product interactive ...providing data to the
machines so that it can learn and it can continue to become more effective these are
sharp mailboxes and your ...for that of course we have
...or the issue of web app which is where we
put our API and where the product has access to it and all of this
manifests itself on the product itself this is what our feed looks like this is what
...platforms our and what's exciting is that this is where we
are seeing giving move from a transactional activity to more engaging we're seeing
people be far more interactive informal social connecting collaborating
about the causes that they care about the charities that are important to them?
And, as I conclude I can't emphasize enough how much this how much
of an impact this is going to have ...really in a fantastic position because
this platform has allowed us to focus exclusively on our goal to
ensure that every great cores gets the funding that requires thank you.
The opportunity to build applications that can change the world has never been greater
each of you now has access to cloud resources that were unimaginable just a
few years ago there's never been a better time to be a developer and
I'm really looking forward to seeing what-you built thank you very much.
All right we'll move to the next chapter of our platform
innovation office there are three core concepts.
In the transformation of office ...a platform.
The first one is about the user experience.
We're opening up the office user experience for all
of your applications in fundamental ways so that
your applications can show up in the context of what
...plus users of office due in office create staff
do get stuff done collaborate communicate we want you to be able
to build applications that fit naturally into those context.
Second we want to go beyond.
Single applications very API in data silos
to us semantically rich graph of data that is available
for you to be able to consume as well as extent.
And, third.
We want to have the capability to reason over that rich
graph and add intelligence into your applications so that not only does
it drive new features or more importantly
...engagement in your applications so those are the tree
concept that fundamentally change office so we want to give you a quick tour of that
so that you can look at what your applications can do to exploit these capabilities and I
and for that I just want to introduce rob ...from our office team to show you some of those hi rob.
So, how can we get started by talking about how we ...moving from office
from mas to office with partners that's great let's
dive right in what we're looking at here is word this is office sixteen when thirty
...and what we see is a solution from doc you sign scott was talking about
them earlier they do digital signatures and they've integrated the our of
their service directly into office using ...new modern ...
...framework it's built on top of html five and javascript communicates the
document through javascript object model let's switch gears and look at another one this is an ad in that
we're building partnering with SAP that makes it easy for me while I'm building a
spreadsheet like my product inventory
information to pull information directly from SAP this is built on top of
...for gateway for microsoft when the great things about the new add-in framework is
that it works across platforms so let's switch over to the browser
...excel online I get to see the same spreadsheet with the same great
add-in experience running in both places it's the same out on the goes everywhere office
goes that's exactly right and in fact let's take a look at excel for
the eye pad and what we see is exactly what you want to have the same solution hosted in
itself ...the eye pad showing the same add-in running for
SAP and this will be released in upcoming months but let me just show you how I could use that?
To connect SAP ...click connect and it does exactly what you want which is connect
...my own premise eighty server hold the content out and
...directly inside of my spreadsheet running on the.
Let's talk about something very different let's talk about making a
...I'm doing this of course want a constant
source of high-quality professional photographs that I can integrate into my slide deck
picket me is a relatively new company that is building just such a service is
provided an ad in here that lets me search through the photos in those service and
paste them directly within powerpoint one of the key things about this
add-in model is that it's a road map for how we're going to do
...ends going forward so let's take a look at the newest member of the
office family sway this is a tool for interactive storytelling that runs
great on the web and renders beautifully mobley and we've
integrated a set of services that make it easy for me to polling contents
we've integrated with picket and ...be delivering an upcoming months
...services will be delivering
...upcoming months the exact same framework and ...model that runs across all of the
endpoints for office that's word excel powerpoint and outlook let's take a
look at people working in outlook professional users handling and managing all their email
dealing with a great deal of information they want to stay up-to-date on who are all these people that
were talking to what we're showing here is an add-in from linked in
that makes it easy for me to do that it pulls the users off the two in CC line it shows them to me
directly in the context of my email so I don't have to leave the flow of how I'm doing my work
weak sales force has built a very similar thing that ...from the two in CC line but also looks
up the companies that are showing up on the male thread so I get to see the people and
...them and sales force but I can see the accounts and I can go right into the
opportunities and take action from here within outlook without leaving the flow of my
...and it's been great to be working with the cells ...they're really
exploit all of the extensions we have across the entire surface area of office
...in excel or ...outlook or in other areas and
build the business processes right into the collaboration
in communications infrastructure that's fantastic to see absolutely outlook is not
just about male outlook is also about my appointments and my calendar ing and,
it has all that information is structured way ...the important things for me is not as being the meeting but getting
there on time or partnering with over to build a solution that does exactly this so here's an ad in that
...has built there I can set and
...reminder to show up ahead of time and make sure that I get to where I need to go
as we switch over here to the I phone what I actually see is I've got a reminder for
...saying slide to get a ride so I'll go ahead and do that it brings up
hoover and it's my pick-up location the cool thing is that
it got my destination because that lived in outlook so outlook knew where I needed to be ...
...knows where I need to go that's great so that shows you how
applications that you bill sharp throughout office they extend beyond
any single application now let's talk a little bit about this graph how are we
building ...graph and exposing the graph to developers,
yeah, that's actually pop it open and take a look at exactly what it looks like so this week
...build we're announcing a preview of the unify eighty
...point for office three sixty five API this builds on top of the
...calendar workloads that we delivered last fall and what it does is make it easy for
developers to get to this data in a unify consistent way so we just popping open a
little API explorer tool that can show us what are some of those request
...response patterns look like so what we use a developer have to do in order to get access to
this rich data what you can see is the URL a pretty simple
...microsoft-dot-com version number and the tenant that I'm connecting to
so make it easy for me in this example the query active directory together list
of users I'm karen from users for a particular departments in this case operations and what I
get back is exactly what you would expect clean well formatted easy-to-understand
...son every developer in the room has a whole tool kit that can parse this and use it to
build great solutions but the point is that this is actually a graph so I can go from an
individual user to drill into their files all I have to do to get to the files from one
drive for business is sticks slash files on the end of the URL and from ...
I see data documents coming back from one drive these are just the files that the
logging user's permission ...that's the powerful concept which is you no longer are going
to different applications for different data you're not going to active directory for users and groups and then
to one drive for files but you're able to traverse the entirety of the graph
with these API exactly right in fact
speaking of groups let's pull up another example office three sixty five has a new concept
for unify modern group that brings together the people and the documents
and conversations encounter that they're having and we're exposing that through the unify ...
...so I can query the active directory for groups that I can navigate through them
defines ...files that belong to those groups so here we actually see stick on
a slash files and it brings up the files associate with that group again trims to the
...user now this notion of logging user is a really common pattern for
people building solutions so we've actually made it super easy there's a me token that you can stick in your
URL to just get back the data for the ...use and that's probably very important because everything here
...the policies and ...that you put into a D so in some sense the
...token gives you access for the user using the applications credentials exactly
right and because now I have access to my information I can go and look at my
calendar just slash events on the end of the URL and that brings back appointments that are alive
and my outlook calendar and ...idea to get to messages last messages and boom
I'm in my inbox coming from exchange and it's just that easy awesome so
how can we talk about the last concept which is how do we go
from here to really building the richness
of intelligence inside of your applications sure so,
this is powered by the office graphs and the thing about the office graph is we talked about
data we talked about ...ends and we really talked about how we can use that to drive a whole
other set of insights we know who are the people that conversations the meeting
in the organizations and what we can do with that is provide additional insights
...they can use that in the preview here to query the graph to get information out
...in addition we're delivering a first party app in the shape of delved that actually
provides me every day with information about what am I working on it helps me search
and discover the contents that my colleagues are using?
There's something funny going on.
Keep going ...
Ok, so, here I am looking at dell and,
what I see is exactly what you'd expect some cards and contact that ...help me stay
up-to-date ...my colleagues are doing so I see an excel notebook that is coming out
...one drive the let's me see here's what my boss built here some cape gis here's an attachment
that lives in email but we've been working with partners to imagine what will it look
like when we have additional third-party signals coming to the graph how can they get into this
notification stream what we see ...opportunities so that's a card from
...force and that's exactly right this is a carbon sales were showing the ...showing information about
...account etc I can navigate down here's information coming from twitter and
believe that we see information coming from
...people are collaborating boards I can navigate directly through and get to that
and, let's actually scroll down a little bit further and what we see is a purchase order coming
from dynamics AX that looks like a super important one so it was great
...made it easy for me to take action on it right so this is no longer now information that is
inside of the office graph that's based on the data of our apps but people
are able to extend the graph with additional edges and nodes that's
all surfacing in doubt that's exactly right wonderful thank you so much ...by much?
That gives you a flavor for how
offices fundamentally changing in fact there's one other SDK that we're launching
in addition to the office graph which is what web SDK for
sky where the ...information where the ability to embed ...
...of your applications video chat and messaging is
now possible so you can build a web app ...mobile app using sky presence information
...embedded inside of your apps this fundamental change.
That we're making ...office.
This fundamental platform shift of office where the users the one
billion plus users of office are available for you is developers this
semantically rich graph that is available for you to consume and extend and
to drive additional engagement through intelligence we believe is going to change
the very fundamental nature of what office is becoming really
a platform ...from us and from you together.
I know you all ...very patiently to hear about windows.
And, it's now time to talk about windows.
Windows ten.
As I said.
Is not just another release of windows it
is a new generation of windows?
It is windows built for this era of more personal
computing.
Where mobility of the experience across devices is
what is paramount not just the mobility of the device?
It's bills such that users can
interact with the variety of devices that are going to be powered
by windows in the most natural ways it could be touch it
can be inks speech mouse and keyboard or even hologram
is also built with the foundation of trust when we talk
about more personal it becomes even more important to know that the
data that you are giving the system is being used to benefit the
Tones of foundational things that drive more personal computing for us.
It is a very different windows in terms of
how we deliver it how we keep it alive.
It's a service we want to make sure.
That for every developer here you have.
The ...why ...the user base that
...are applications can target we also have a unify
platform everything from rats very pi to the holographic
computer is one developer platform that means you're scales apply
across all of the places windows runs and lastly.
...one unify store.
That means the economic return for what you do on
windows.
Spans the entire install base and the growing.
Device family of windows.
So, I'm really excited about where we are in this johnny.
...most excited about what.
We together are going to do in the coming year with windows stand
...all the video.
And, bodies ...our consumer ...our enterprise customers are demanding.
Making available ...up.
And, ...that ...earlier phase ...in any other time in the history of.
Follow developers it is so great to be back here
build to talk about windows ten.
Scottish ...shared that
...aspiration is for customers for end-users to love using windows ten.
we also have this aspiration for you to developing for windows ten?
Our goal is to make windows ten the most attractive development
platform ever enabling you to build the most innovative applications,
applications that
your customers never before possible.
Integrate ...honda into your apps.
Integrate xbox live ensure apps giving your customers awards
and achievements or bring them a wife with the avatar.
And, natural ...interactions you're apps like penn.
For speech turn your apps in the hologram ...
With windows chan.
Were targeting the broadest device family ever from devices
with small screens.
Like phones.
So, large screens.
Going beyond and all one pc to our
...wall manage displays the surface hub.
...devices with no screen at all like the ...things.
Or hollow ...
We're talking about one platform.
...single out
a single binary they can run across all of these devices.
When we look at the search terms?
In the store.
We compare what people are searching for and phones to with searching for and pcs we see
that forty percent of the search terms are exactly the same.
Customers are looking for your apps in all of these places.
With apple you choose to invest in our west or mac OS
...you choose to invest and drawing or chrome
Windows is the only ecosystem.
That what you bring your apps to all of these devices efficiently.
Now there are many ways to gaps on windows.
What's talk about the windows store.
Abstract come from the windows store.
Come with a set of promises to the end-user your customers.
For end-users applications in the windows ...very
easy to discover not only within the store itself but ...
...assume a show you how windows applications can be discovered throughout the windows experience.
Apps from the windows store.
Will be easy and fast to install?
An ...wants.
And, they will never junk up your system.
Commerce with the windows star will be convenience and trusted with
the wide variety of global payment insurance.
Not just the credit cards we're use here
in the us but payment instruments like always pay for china.
And, today we're announcing carrier billing.
Not only for windows phones but for all windows devices.
And, windows what the largest carrier going footprint any ecosystem.
With connections to ninety mobile operators.
Our experience with phones so this is great.
For our customers that don't have credit cards but you have phones.
And, this is great for developers because our experience
of phones that in emerging markets application
...have gone up by a factor of a times.
When carrier going is
enabled and now it's available across all windows devices?
The new windows store.
Offer new business models and ways to monetize for all of our windows
developers including subscriptions affiliate referrals
and updated advertising SDK
...support for video ads and install tracking one set of tools one
set of processes for you to reach customers across all of these devices and
engage with the customers all over the planet with reviews and ratings
and other tools that are available in the windows store.
And, today we're introducing the windows store for business.
Businesses and schools can customize the windows store.
Hiring applications in the public ...they want to make more easily
discoverable recommend to their employees are students.
And, the window store for business will support business payment methods by purchase
orders opening up a new vein of opportunity for windows
developer's to engage with windows enterprises worldwide.
That's make all this worthwhile for developers we know we need to get windows
tend to be broadly adopted quickly so we started by making it
available as a free upgrade for the first-year.
And, now are investing in making it easy
for consumers and businesses to adopt windows ten worldwide.
Today we're sharing our goal our goal is that within two or three years of
windows
...release ...one billion devices running windows ten.
No, other platform version in
any ecosystem is available on one billion devices.
Current estimates for google placate cat is
that a little over five hundred million devices I always say this is lower than that.
With windows ten there'll be
one billion devices ready to run your applications.
Now we've already ...working with many of you and your
gamma laps embracing this new universal windows platform working
and doing things that you can't do ...any other platform.
We're delighted that companies like disney netflix
wine sweater so many more working with us to build amazing applications
for the one billion devices that will run windows ten.
Let's take a look at some of the work by these partners.
Five-star quite high wind the work being done by usa today which has been a great windows developer
and a great partner today they have a separate code base
for phone application and ...PC application they want to bring
these code base ...they can focus on great quality
in great functionality and take that application to new windows devices.
So, here.
You see the usa today is live tile from their new universal windows application.
On this pc ...great
work with touch and keyboard shortcuts.
The application uses
our standard our standard platform controls so resize is
and re flows as the application is resize on the desktop snapping
Allowing me to do more work.
Now ...can never get enough reading about dupes basketball teams
let's go there and you can see here the app the article
...greatly in the ...great in this size
windows now this application is also using our platform capabilities
to automatically store state in the cloud to the state of the me reading
this articles available ...all these divide all my windows devices or ...
devices that might want to access the same state so now ...pick up ...windows phone.
At the same binary running here the same ...tile.
...run it and the articles opening up to the exact same place
leveraging the state that was automatically
shared to the cloud one binary one code base all working across phones how
...pc now usa today wants to bring your application to the xbox.
We'll do a lot of reading of articles on the XBox they wanted
...the application filter.
The application down ...video feeds.
So, they invest in one-hour
...universal windows application code base and here it is running on the
Filtered down to just video ...navigating in ...the ...different
...navigate down I see the same video controls that are available across the windows ten
platform.
Navigating down further and the control or I get recommended video
articles of investment is
one universal windows application they now have phones tablets
pcs interactive television all covered with one code base and one ...
Now let's take a look at the work ten
cents done with their we chat application we chats an incredible phenomenon
...just crossed five hundred-million monthly active users gone forty percent
year over year they've been a great application for windows phone users.
Here they are on my windows ...ten ...one of the brain
...chat to windows PC and tablets so they made
...investment in their silverlight application on the phone
team spent about approximately one month they now have a universal windows app there
runs great on the phones and we'll also now be available on the desktop
...experiences for the desktop so let's look at we chat on the desktop.
Now on the phone ...noticed shannon sent me a message.
I have which ...pc but now we can access that new
...from the notification center.
I click on the notification center message from we ...this same binary running both places.
Open the message and ...asking for the file and here they've done some tailoring
to except drag-and-drop from the desktop all
with one universal windows application that's running across these devices.
For usa today and we chat ...just a couple of
the many great apps coming to the universal windows platform if you manage joe bell
fury will join us and show how universal one is apps are going
to enable you to do things you never thought possible on the phone.
And, alex ...going to join to talk about our universe
...windows apps you never thought possible on hall ...
Now partners like but these are giving us great feedback as
engage across all these devices with the universal windows platform.
Netflix ...they can ...the rap sufficiently everywhere.
It seemed trivia crap ...my favorite does a great game of
...frac three hat tours of developing
...is four times faster and developing for engineering iowa
Let me just.
Say thank you for your early engagement and the universal
windows platform so we can bring your applications to life.
So, that was about.
That was all about new universal windows apps.
But, today we ...talk also about your current code.
Your current apps windows
is always embraced a wide variety of technologies to build rate apps
and today we're going to announce for new ones.
For new ways to average your existing code and skills.
For new ways to reduce the cost an effort
making it easy ...to bring applications to the windows store.
For new ways to ...white one
billion windows ten customers at home at school.
Let's start.
By talking about the web.
Many of you have websites that provide great functionality to your customers
today I'm announcing that you can reuse your current server hosted
website code ...
And, take advantage of the rich capabilities of the universal windows
platform.
Have your website
send notifications to give your website arrive tile have your website
...reports on a do went out purchases integrate with xbox live in more?
This will help your websites reach new customers and the
...windows customers in new ways.
But, see this ...action.
So, to demonstrate this we're going to use a website
twenty two tracks which deejays across europe used to
...it's a very rich
...which website uses web gl.
Brief
...to the browser re sizing it's a great website
...that john is a register ...website with the windows store and then I've installed.
That application on this machine.
Whoops there it is and it's going to open up as an application the web the server
hosting web code can detect whether the code is executing inside
a browser tab or inside an application frame when it's inside
...application frame.
In ...can call the whole universal windows platform so now when I close
the browser tab the websites gone but now that it's an app when I ...
The app twenty ...tracks can now send me
...notification click on the notification and I come back
to their app likewise now the twenty tracks is using ...can
detect the running as an app they can efficient conveniently offer
in out purchases to other customers for the music leveraging
the commerce capabilities of the windows store so this is just fantastic wedding
web site developers leverage all of ...server ...code.
And, take advantage of the
capabilities of the windows platform and the windows store.
So, now the second technology I want to announce today.
To enable you to bring new applications to the windows store.
Is actually the most popular technology within the windows development community?
Dot net and win thirty two.
There's over sixteen million dot net and win thirty two applications being used every
In the windows user base.
Ranging from some amazing games.
...some of the most important line-of-business apps used worldwide
visit testament to the great work being done by windows developer's so
...so excited to announce that will be adding support for
bringing your dot net and win ...into the windows store
and take advantage of all of the new universal windows platform capabilities.
Show you how this works.
...use app that's used by log by customers worldwide.
One of the best when thirty-two applications ever adobe photoshop.
So, here you see adobe photoshop elements.
In the windows store.
Now I ...earlier the promise the windows store makes the ...
...applications will be very efficiently installed on installed on never junk up your
system.
We know the same time win
thirty two applications can do anything to windows system.
So, we've learned from app ...enterprise application virtualization
technology we've adopted it through the windows store so now when
...two and dot net applications ...down from the windows store and they
run an isolated way from the rest of the systems we can deliver on that promised
end-users to deliver great end-user experience.
So, here is photo shop you can see it is the full photoshop experience with great
performance ...prove that see with the full limits my photoshop capabilities.
Helping scott out here so there you go but
all come down from the windows store.
...very exciting share.
That later this year adobe we building bringing
photo shop elements and premier elements to the windows store.
So, the ...great support for apps built using web code.
Dot net and win
...code enabling you to use your current code ...extend them using windows
tens new platform capabilities and the white customers
across the one billion windows ten devices.
Now the third technology I
am announcing today will enable developers to reuse nearly all
of the java in CPlus-plus code from an injury phone up to
...apps for phone's running windows ten.
To make this possible.
Windows phones will include ...
enjoyed subsystem we're an app can be written that takes advantage
of the enjoyed code but also the extensions you right in the windows platform to
...the windows user to show you how this works please welcome
...stage agnes.
My name is ...nascar growing and one of the project of years working on the technology that
will enable you to build great windows apps by reusing a lot of the
code you have written for andrea here I have an unruly device.
And, on it I'm running the choice hotels
up choice hotels is the highest rated up and it's category makes
very easy for travelers to find a great hotel.
They're going to switch to windows phone.
On this windows phone
...also running the choice hotels app.
This app is reusing the code you just so running on the other device.
I'd like to look for hotels nearby.
The app is taking advantage of the windows location
To find.
Hotels in san francisco california.
Okay.
...have a switch to ...device which.
Well, let's try that again.
Research right as I scroll through the results.
You can see that the windows graphics in touch just work and the
app is running smoothly it's running the windows security container to
...trustworthy experience for windows users.
I'd like to go back.
And, as I hit the back button.
Please note that the apps ...integrated with the windows navigation model.
I'd like to ...different city so I'm going to type in.
Seattle.
With a built in windows keyboard.
So, I has just shown you.
However, that can take efficiently reuse
...code to deliver a great experience on windows.
And, tomorrow's keynote we will show you how you
can light up your absolute experience with native windows features such as
lifestyles and with microsoft services thank you terry back to you and
So, windows chance can enable you to reuse.
Your web code your dot net and when theory to code your?
...and CPlus-plus code
to build amazing new applications bringing the code over.
Extending it putting in the windows store.
And, reaching one billion windows ten customers.
Finally.
The fourth technology to build
grades new universal windows applications.
Is objectives C?
So, today we're announcing that you'll be able to compile
the same objective C code.
That's being used in
on us applications within visual studio on windows.
...you know, whatever exact code and extend it with the capabilities
only found on the windows platform.
Let's take a walk.
So, here in this directory we have an iowa
...math dream.
Even see here the X code project
file for math dream you can see the natives
in zip files for the UI.
...the classes directory you can see the dot m files.
For the objective C.
Using ...okay we're announcing today we've converted the X code project
file into a visual studio solution so let's open up here.
In visual studio.
You can see full support for this visual studio projects.
Objective C.
Great syntax highlighting support ...expect from visual
studio including highlighting all of the weirdness of objectives C.
We've taken this application.
And, now we can debugged and execute this tower map on windows.
You can see ...a relatively sophisticated
...uses you I can't uses core animation on windows.
The performance is good but it also works with mouse and such.
Can do very complex arithmetic to do that?
But, actually that's the wrong answers what's
...justice to the right number of apples and you can see not only
...correctly do math.
What this application has been extended so offer
me an xbox live achievement for doing the proper ...equation?
Now you might be wondering if this actually works.
Will work for more complex app?
Now usually announces kind of
thing would say coming soon well in this case it's different
we've been working with some great development partners and
bringing their applications to windows using this technology already.
And, today I'm very excited to share.
But, this is how king.
Brought candy crash saga of the windows phone.
The app has four-and-a-half star reviews forty thousand reviews king brought the
apt to windows following the very fast time the market very
few code modifications and it's a great ...and now king
will be releasing more titles for windows ten ...
So, there's actually one more thing we're going to do.
To help make it easy.
For you to build greats.
Windows, windows applications.
And, that is we need to get you some greats hardware.
In order to start today by giving everyone here
are brand new HP specter two and one.
This is a great device.
Compared to macrophone it's thinner it's lawyer
has longer battery wife of course it has a touch display and
our encourage everyone here.
To join
the windows insider program engage with us on this platform.
And, help shape it for your needs.
But, fleas do the upgrade to windows ...from your hotels wi-fi.
...wi-fi ...the conference.
today we talked about ...one billion windows ten devices
the unique capabilities of the windows ten platform and our commitment to a
broad-range of technologies to leverage your skills and
your current code to build great outs.
And, ...got so much more to come so please welcome joe ...
All right good morning.
Hello, it's nice to be here at ...with all of you so,
you got a chance to look at how the universal windows platform is going to enable all of you and
tons of other developers to build great compelling apps and what I'm here to do
as terry said is to talk about how we're going to enhance the windows
user experience so that end-users on lots and lots of devices but
in particular I'm going to focus on the pc how end-users
will be able to discover and engage with all of the apps that
you and we right we know that great technology for building apps is just
part of the story you need users to engage with them so I want to show you some of the work we're doing that's going to
make that possible ...I'm going to wrap up with one more cool demo of how the universal
windows platform enables new devices and new kinds of actions on devices
so let me just jump right in and get started so, I have here a very recent build
of windows ten for the pc and I'm going to begin on the start menu I want to
show you some of the work we've been doing to continue to tweak the design
and improve the visuals in the interaction so you'll see
what I've got here we think is pretty close to what we expect to have
one we're done although of course we're going to continue to take feedback from our insiders you'll
notice there's new beautiful live tile animations that
helped draw people's attention to the apps and the app data for the things that they've
pinned you'll notice we've clean the layout up a bit for those
of you insiders who kind of surprised us with your enthusiasm
for windows seven aero glass you'll notice the translucent see here's the blur
effect that you start windows seven so we're trying to bring some of that field back
we've got the most used apps here we're putting file explore settings our all
laps at the bottom were bringing jump lists back in so you can see here's file explore with
jump ...and this work for other apps as well thank you?
But, the thing I ...sort of focus on a little bit
is this space right here where in this case I have an installed ...out for a
little while so the system is going to give us a smart suggestion for
an app in the store that is going to be one that's suitable for me as I'm using
my pc on the client we know which apps are launching ...which apps you're installing
so we're able to communicate with the store and bring down suggestions that are personalize for
you to help users learn about great new apps that are available for them to trout
and their pc and as time goes by we
reuse that space in a smart way to help script the
...discovery of apps first but then
their engagement later so five installed
an app as you see here for a little while that space becomes the recently installed
out the user confine the app they can revisit and if they use it enough it'll move
its way up into the most used section automatically and of course at
any time the user can drag from left to right to take any of those apps and pin them as
full live tiles so think of this as the users lifecycle of discovery
and engagement and re-use which ...trying to script right into the start menu?
There's a whole other area that users are engaging with where we want to
bring some beauty and new ideas for how they can get value out of
their pc experience and that is the lock screen so I want to show you some of what we're doing on
lock to help users discover and engage with the value
in windows ecosystem so imagine your user and this morning you wake up and you
turn on your pc or ...tablet and you get this beautiful lock screen when this case
you're using our windows spotlight feature which you could choose to use or not on your
lock screen and it provides a service driven personalized stream
of information on your lock screen for you so maybe in a week you wake up and
the earth screen looks a little different in this case you say yourself man that is a beautiful
and striking image and you're so enthused by it that you move your mouse the upper
right click on the hot spot like what you see here's a place where you have the opportunity
did train our service on which things are interesting to you in this case I
can I find out this is the navajo loops which backs it's a cool looking trail I might vote that I love it and
then I'll get more images like that time goes by one day ...
you see an image like this now this is because we are able
as I said to understand on the client what your use of the pc is
and communicate that data to the service to give personally relevant suggestions ...want you
to imagine a user who's had windows ten for six weeks or eight weeks and they haven't
used courts on a yet they haven't tried it out and because they haven't tried it out
our services able to provide the client with a set of options that we can display
to help users learn about discovered engage with value in the windows ecosystem
and in this case you see the image that suggestive of core ton
...a few more hot spots to give you more information if you click on the upper-left
will give you a preview of what the court tiny ...would be like you could click
give-me a try that unlock your pc will reveal the core tiny user
experience and now you can try it out for yourself keep in mind this is personalized
and it's informed by what you do on the ...so ...you're a our user has been using
...on it you're not going to see this imagine time goes by you get more beautiful images
your desktop pc or your tablet always feels fresh with all this great stuff and
then one morning you might see an image like this as a tablet user.
You maybe have not tried out all the capabilities of your tablet to do stuff like beautiful art
work using the pen in fact here's an app that gives you that kind of
benefit that you haven't used so far and there's a few
extra hot spots to help you learn about it when you click in the upper-left it you're
the fresh paint app that's in the stores described at anytime you could choose to click
get it now your pc you unlock your pc jump
right into the store and then you'd be able to install the app and try it out and then a few
days go by and you're back to seeing your beautiful images we call this feature
the windows spotlight and it's optional any user can turn it on with their
lock screen and then get the value of learning about new things in
the windows ecosystem in a way that's tailored for you and also get this beautiful
stream of images on your lock screen so that's another way we're going to help users
...discover value in the windows ecosystem
okay I want to show you that yet another part of our user experience that we've
continue to ...with feedback from our insiders
which has a lot of relevance to users discovering and engaging
with apps that's core tunnel so of course we've done lots of demos of
court on I'm not going to go through the end-user features of core town but I'll show you a ...of
...the core tunnel will assist with engagement I should quickly
point out there's some new you why that we have for courts on ...you all haven't seen yet you'll be getting this
...a flight coming up soon over here I have access to the core
...at home ...this out you can see the notebook
your reminders your favorite places of course here is the
courts on the place where she gives you proactive suggestions
and information-based on your interests you can see I follow microsoft's stock I
followed the mariners baseball team I care about sports news in general the
seattle seahawks so on so ...are those are personal interests that I've educated core
...about which are things that are relevant to me and you'll see how this comes up again later now
what are the really high use cases for that
core taught at control right there is people typing
to ask questions get information but also to launch apps and we think that's
a great relevant way to help people discover new value as well so imagine I
am running star wars commander on my pc I've got
installed and I run it a lot I might start typing into launch
the app and you'll notice in this case there's a new star wars rebels app and the star
wars ...family and we're going to promote right up the top of this new apt that's available
for you to install ...I will point out because you may be sitting there
...that's not that much promotion we've done some user testing on this and we're going to bulk
up that store gap tiled provide a little bit more information more along the lines of what
you sign starts we think this is going to be quite helpful way
to discover new apps that are available in the store now terry mention this
...to mention the notion that we care about natural interaction we want core
time to represent a single wafer users on windows to interact
with all kinds of capabilities that are built throughout the ecosystem so we're connecting
core thomas typed natural language and spoken natural language deeply
into your apps ...doing this in two ways this is quite a bit farther than we did with
windows phone before so I want to show you the range of sorts of things that are possible I
want to imagine in one case I want to bring up the app to do a task with the app and
the other case I simply want court trying to get something done for me
using the technology that's part of an app so here's a couple of examples hey courts
...started chat with terry my arson on vibrant.
Starting to chat with terry myers and now in this case I gave a
natural language query I said I want to start chat I said it was with terry I said I wanted her to do
it on ...and in this case she opens up the app and in my chat
context with the previous chatting we were doing like keep going with my chat so that's sort of a deep
...launching kind of task but
there's a whole class of tasks where we want courts honor to represent being
personal assistant that can get things done for you even using the
capabilities that are written into the apps that are part of the windows ecosystem so I can ask for
tyler to execute commands in apps and get confirmation right under canvas
hey core tunnel will tell terry
...sen I'm running really late using vibe or.
Okay,
message terry myers and on vibe or myers and I'm running really late.
Sounds good.
Yes, yep,
message sent ok there we go so you
get the idea here now in this case ...asked court
...to do something using an app and in that case the app you I didn't need to get displayed so
core thomas canvas was able to do the disambiguation if I want to I could go right here
...click the link to open the app but that's not what I need to do there's
court on helping me get stuff done okay so I've talked about the lock screen
...start screen court time there's one other really big feature in windows ten that has
relevance this conversation to all of us developers and that is
...project spartan project spartan products part,
you know, I have to admit are pr team has been giving me and
us a hard time because they say it's not a great idea to keep saying project spartan when that's not
really the name of the web would you like to hear the name of the new web browser in windows
...ok let's run on.
Microsoft edge is the browser built for windows
ten ...be available on the widest range of windows ten devices and for us
the name refers to the idea of being on the edge of consuming
and creating it refers to the developer notion of being closest to the modern
capabilities of the web so, it is a browser that end-users will think about
forgetting things done for things like note-taking on the internet for a great
way of reading and consuming content and it's a browser that has core
...built in so it learns the things that you care about and helps you get things done I'm not going to
go show any of that stuff we've shown that before as developers ...few reasons that you're going
to care about microsoft edge you're going to care about the blazing fast core technology
that's inside it you'll hear more about that in a talk tomorrow you're going to care that we're writing it as
a universal windows app proving out the platform and you're also going to care because we're going
to make it helped users discover and engage with your apps and
your sites so they come over here ...show you some of what we're doing there are
come down here to the economy the task bar which now has a completely different
and better meeting that it has for a while and open up microsoft edge
now the first thing that I want to show you that's new is the new tab page they
were adding to microsoft at today in IEEE the task of starting a new tab and starting
new web browsing happens over a billion times a day so this is a heavily used piece of
URI and you'll see here how we're going to take advantage of core
thomas presence in the browser and understanding of you along with an understanding of
value ...the ecosystem to give users a great way to start their
web browsing experience or discover other things you can see of course I can type to enter
web address or do a search up here are my top sites
and in some cases there's an app available for these sites in the store we make that
...available as I scroll down you'll see
here's some featured apps that were showing here's a lot of news stories that are relevant
to me in fact my sports favorites that you saw in court sauna and mike stock watch list in
court on those are represented right here in the new tap page that's an example of course
...helping to compose this in a way that's useful to me so
that's new tab and we've been testing this a ton and
we're optimistic about its opportunity to help people discover and connect with work
that you all do on the web and in apps there's another big thing that we're
doing and microsoft edge that's has huge relevance to you and that
is enabling users to engage with your sites and give you a shot
at starting to write some web code which you may and put into an app ...web
extensions built into microsoft edge so I'm going to show you a couple of web
extensions this-is html and javascript
like web extensions using web standards that people have been writing for fire fox and chrome for quite a
while we've grabbed a couple of these from chrome with just a few
minor modifications and we're letting them up right here in microsoft edge so the first thing
...read it users do we have yes, come on,
you must be right ...for those of you who are our ready users maybe in
the some of the other browsers you've tried the red enhancement ...which modifies the
mark-up on read it to make it easier to fight images and scroll pages what
we've brought that to microsoft edge as I said just a few changes so as I scroll down
here you'll see the web has been altered via this little pop
print here that I can use to expand and his little pick
...just kills me to as I look at this cute it's a cat or a mouse I don't even know
and as I scroll down here you'll see the never-ending read it modifies the page
say continue expanded as we go it was
virtually no work to take this from the chrome extension store and run this is
...html and javascript just running here ...part of an extension
...another example which certainly matters in terms of user engagement up here
you'll see we've added a pin trust extension to the browser tool bar and when I
click that this is going to interact with the
markup on the page to show all of the images that were generated by the red enhancement
...and now I can find tons of things here that are incredibly cute that I might tend to one of the
many pinchers cute animal boards that I and I know all of you keep just for
this sort of thing so with projects part with microsoft edge and
the new support for these extensions you'll see how we're going to enable
people to discover and engage with code that you're
propped up on the web and as I said of course you could bring that into an app as well so you
see infer engagement the start screen the lock screen you've seen
...and microsoft edge all helping people discover value ...the windows ...
...what I'm going to do is change gears and talk about how the windows platform
and universal windows apps make devices more valuable
to end-users in general we have a vision an idea that
the windows platform and apps written for it should be able to flex to different
screen sizes and different input methods not by writing
separate code but by having a platform that's smart enough to do in fact
even dynamically on the same device we call this feature continuum it's a promise to
...made along with our OEM partners that devices
...so I want to show you some of the
ways that continuum is evolving and I want to show you some of the ways that
you're apps can light up a great continuum experience I'm going to start
with eight-inch tablet this is a lenovo thinkpad it's running full windows it's
got intel compatible part and the first thing you might notice of course I'm going to use this in tablet
...you're looking at tablet mode but for those of you
pay attention closely and especially if you've given us feedback our
touch start in tablet mode we've simplified here we made the live tiles
bigger this looks very familiar to windows eight users and the extra stuff
you're most use list your sign in things like file explore settings the
our switch are all over here I can navigate ...all ...all laps
or showed nicely in this list we now have jumped lists working in here
in a nice?
Way with animation so on so it's really easy for me to navigate around my apps
of course down here and the ...the system tasks which are I've got
my task switching button which I can use to switch between lots of apps here's X so that's
the excel for windows ten and I'm going to do here's jump into maps
and do some navigation and the maps app here and I want to show you how this will scale to
of more full pc like experience so, here I am in my map I'm going
to go up here choose the favorites menu and down here in this panel
on the bottom we're first going to navigate to new york city and I want to point out that the system
UI now includes a global back button so I'll hit the back
button the app navigate back and ...navigate to ...now what I'm going to do I want you
to think about me using this in a very natural touch friendly way but now since
the full pc ...bring it back to my office ...just going to docket
in here and when I do I want you to notice how the maps app
experience changes to adapt the panel that was on the bottom when I
wasn't portrait mode is now on the left side and in fact when I,
you know, restore this window
I've now got my excel I've got my powerpoint all here running
in a familiar way with windows that I can minimize and restore in pc
mode so that's an example of continuum really helping me ...a small
...the next example I want to show you that's new is here on this surface pro
three where I have a rich complex ...
thirty two app this is ...desks my it's a high-end heavily
used very popular three-D authoring at and, you know,
if you notice the you I've got lots of tool bar's and ...down here I've got the timeline or it might
edit animation of my three-D character but imagine I'm an artist so I might use
this docked with the big-screen keyboard mouse might use it like this but sometimes I'm going to
remove the keyboard entirely and use it like a tablet and in this case here's
...within thirty two app responding to that change in state in the system and adapting
it's you ...and now I can use touch or I could use the pen to be able to
do things like mark-up right on the character maybe it maybe I'm now going to be in
this note where in this mode where I want to take notes for people
at my team share my thoughts on the character the app flex is to take
advantage of the use of the pen and touch as opposed to mouse and keyboard
and in that case using win thirty two now I have one last thing I want to show thank you?
I have one last thing I want to show up so far we've shown this
continuum feature working with our shell and with apps on the PC and watching the
pc device flex across these form factors but we have a
vision that not only the pc can benefit from flexibility and use
of input devices and screen sizes so ...can the phone so today
we're excited to show for the first-time continuum
for phones built into windows ten so let me give you look at how that
works so over here I have now I've I should point out we need new hardware for this
and I don't have that hardware working today fact we're going to try demo of that ...session on
thursday so you're seeing a simulation I'm going to do is connect my phone and.
Let's see you get this going.
Once I
connect my phone I want you to think of this I've got a bluetooth keyboard a bluetooth mouse
and a screen just a screen that I'm connecting via html I
ok so because this phone software has all the core component tree that's highly
shared between the pc things like bluetooth keyboard mice their supported and,
you might notice I'm not sure if the shot shows this but at the top of my phone street now it says
...for mouse and keyboard controller I could tap that then get essentially a mouse pad on
my phone but I don't need to do that because I have a full bluetooth mouse and
keyboard right here up here on the monitor you'll notice this looks very familiar I mean
...the same start menu with tiles I had my phone now displayed like a
start menu and I want to start running apps to give you a sense of how
well the phone experience transforms through continuing to give you
a very PC like experience first launch powerpoint this is
...version of powerpoint that comes with the phone and,
what you see on the big-screen here sure looks like the version of powerpoint that you would
see a pc because in fact it is the same code as the version of
powerpoint that you would download from the store and see on a pc I can do things
like use my mouse and keyboard to create a new slide ...go up here use the ribbon
to insert pictures remember this is my phone so as I'm inserting
the photos I bring up my photos this is the camera role of my phone and
the photos that I've synched from one drive I'll choose an appropriate desert picture from a
trip I made to utah and I'll insert that into my powerpoint presentation
...completely natural and familiar way using the keyboard and
mouse let's look at some other examples ...click here to go
into male and the outlook mail client that comes with windows ten
pcs and comes with phones is now viewed and it looks completely familiar here's
my mail folders I can choose a message in my inbox and over here
...click the reply button or I have the full our of the word engine embedded
...outlook for doing replies and there's the familiar ribbon you can see here and,
is asking me to update the latest expense report eric's going to give me
the december expenses so I'm going to switch over here to excel where we're doing
arcs spence reporting and you'll see here's excel the universal
windows app excel running on the phone but looking the same as it
...on the pc I'll choose the my expense reporting app and look at this my
phone just buzz I got a text from eric right there I'm going to click
to navigate on my phone screen separately to my text app ...
...hold to get the context ...choose copy because I'm going to copy from that
tax ...here to my a december cell
and of course my brain is wired to know the keyboard shortcuts for all these apps
I'll hit control v to pace I'll use my task switch or to come back to
the outlook e-mail client and I can do a quick reply and sent?
Think about this.
With continuum for phones we believe
...screen can be your pc.
Imagine that your company has a touchdown space where anyone could connect
their tablet or their phone took keyboards mice and screens and then use their
apps with their data and the full our of a keyboard and mouse
or imagine you're on vacation and your hotel room can become a
theater or you connect your phone to the screen you let your kids watch a movie while you use
the second screen to catch up on your email
I imagine the effect this can have on mobile first countries or individuals could
be as productive with the phone that they're buying if they can't buy a full
pc so what we're trying to show here today with continuum is
our unique vision for phones and enabling them to scale-up to a full
pc like experience and what we have so far is just the first step
because it requires all of you writing these universal windows apps
whose you why can scale and it just a different form factors input types and
screen sizes as I said this capability will require new devices that can
drive dual screen and you'll hear more about them later so that is my quick look
at how we're going to help all of you and our end-users discover value in the windows
ecosystem on the lock screen on the start screen with court tunnel with microsoft edge and how we're
going to enable great new devices with continuum and I'm now
...to ...the stage alex
...man who's going to tell you even more about some great new devices?
Thank you joe and good morning everyone now georgia
showed you how to do incredible things with windows from the little screen to
the big-screen now I
get the pleasure to show you how to do incredible things with windows on
...screens at all with the same familiar tools and skills
you already have it's so real being here today less than one
hundred days since the mix hologram with our world less than one
hundred days ago we showed you how windows holographic amplifies what
is human about each of us humans live
in the real-world and we should not be confined to the virtual or just
the digital we experience life in three-dimensions
we move we see and we
here in three-dimensions our dreams fantastic
call or entrepreneur all start in the real-world.
Windows holographic embraces this notion of experiencing life in
three-dimensions by mixing digital content writing to your world
writing to your life with more reality than ever before now the truth
of the matter is people not devices are mobile and we
are ready for technology to move beyond devices to move beyond
screens and pixels and to move beyond today's digital borders
now in january we showed you glamorous of this holographic
landscape.
Go immerse of this more natural
way of interacting with digital content we introduce microsoft
hollow lance the world's first and only fully untapped
third holographic computer and I have
to admit we have been humbled by the outpouring of enthusiasm
spanning from consumers to businesses and the response we received
from developers like yourselves has been remarkable
on behalf of the entire microsoft team thank you we
share your enthusiasm and today we take the next step in
...bailing the windows holographic platform focus on you
...dreamworks the creators the windows
developer's so let's get started by
taking a tour of windows holographic and to help us with that please
help me welcome stage one of the creative minds behind hologram ...daring.
My dear and ...alex.
Now before we start let me explain to set up a little bit
darrin is wearing out hollow lengths and he sees this globe poll
...showed you january ride in his world.
Now we also have discussed them camera ...over here so the you can see the hologram
up on the screens as if the camera is wearing a hollow lance now
when we introduced windows holographic the globe was just a
slide.
Today ...is experiencing it as a universal windows
app and guess what it's running on windows stan ...windows holographic.
This is life with hologram and as you can see
darrin has customized space.
Instead of digging through menus everything is right where he
wants it.
Whether it's microsoft edge photos are video apps.
These are simply universal windows apps ...
...place this hologram so whether it's a slate on the wall or something a little
bit more dimensional like my loyal companion fang
here hey buddy you can customize your space the way you want.
Now I want to add something to my space so I'm going to pull out my holographic start menu.
And, I'm going to open up escape on
the worst keeping in touch so I'm going to take the people the matter most to me.
I ...to this wall right here.
That way every time I walk into this room all see
...smiling faces and be inspired to reach out to them.
We all creatures of habit and we do different things in different spaces
in our homes this stage as an example is modeled after
...apartment, yeah, and,
this is where I hang out my apartment and surround myself with the applications that I want to access
or just check out for example.
And, planning a trip to hawaii and a couple weeks so I place this awesome whether
...over here so when I'm moving around I can easily glance
at it reference it and understand what the weather's going to be like when I get there hopefully still hot.
Then if I look up here on the wall to my left I've got a video player.
Simply reach out
...the actual what deer and have things ...around the house?
Should confine to watching just on one wall
...be able to take his entertainment with him anywhere
in remain hands-free as he does it, yeah, so, all I need to say is follow me?
Now wherever I go my house my entertainment tags along.
All right.
And, we're gets ...I'm going.
I simply place it and.
...scale ...as big as I want.
That's not something just a video player does every single universal windows app says
the same capabilities for example, I place the calendar over here because ...alex
...tell you I'm late for pretty much every meeting so this makes it a guy like
me makes a lot easier for me to check in and see what I've got coming up next
we're discovering uses for ...every day if we know with all you hear
build ...minds towards it we're going to be discovering new uses every second of an
...time available see out there thank you there and.
As you just saw holographic computing can
seamlessly.
Connected digital world with real-life this makes reality grants
...permission to reinvent productivity by creating experience
is not possible ...any other device or any other platform
back in january we ask you to imagine an architect walking around
...designs while clients review them remotely now the construction
industry is a multi-billion-dollar industry yet many of their
processes have ...unchanged over the past few months we have had
a great honor to partner with an organization that has been transforming
the construction industry for over sixty years so let's take a sneak peek at
how holographic computing enabled by windows stand is fundamentally
changing how they think about architecture construction and collaboration.
Architects are dealing ...shapes and spaces in line and, agreements three-D and,
then you need to translate ...set ...
Poland's ...completely paradigm ...provides design solutions for architects and
structural engineers anything that involves getting dirty is our business.
Literally hundreds of enterprises can be represented on a job site
...the best way those companies have ...with each ...
is paper drawings but people aren't good at visualizing three-D microsoft
head-mounted self-contained computer that lets you see kilograms.
A physical model is that ...focus point for
...collaborate around you get the hologram with the flexibility with
...run quick ...say ...broaden the toyota that you suggested
you say that mounts go off the screen and holographic space in your
...interacting with the hologram with ...the thing that we can do for architects
...really give them which higher confidence around decision-making ...we can do that is we cannot
...themselves in the same that building and state
...and other buildings but ...moi.
Visualizing design data ...the contents of real environment
is much better way to make sure that ...is implemented correctly.
Microsoft follow lines allows you to collaborate with somebody regardless of
distance like they were ...
a part where they're trying to this door ...bye time looking at this
...for interacting with that about a problem that we can
say and being able to solve that problem with
all the data that we need in front of us as.
...I'm talking about ...enterprise construction I always
compared to people trying to make music together each one of them is contributing to the
harmony ...they all should be completely ...by greater says I've been doing this for a while ...
lot of these new things coming go moi expect in five years
we'll all be interacting with the world?
Follow gramm's are already being sculpted by some of the most
creative people around now with this ability to design and shape
...grams you have a new medium to express
their creativity to visualize your work and share ideas your digital
creations become so much more relevant when they come to life in the real-world but that's
just the beginning of what hologram can enable windows holographic also provides
you with a unique opportunity to change how you teach and learn ...
...effective weights.
On january twenty first we actually to imagine
a surgeon learning a procedure without picking up a scalpel.
Since then we have partner with an institution accustomed to thinking beyond
the possible and to show us what they have been up to please help me welcome
onstage professor mark result from case western reserve university
in our team member michelle hi mark ...more.
Cellmark is part of a team from case western
in the cleveland clinic we invited them to use windows holographic to advance
medical education beyond what is possible what today's state of the
art taken away thanks alex today we use a combination of cadavers and
medical illustrations to teach students anatomy this is the curriculum and hasn't drastically changed
over a hundred-years because ...simply hasn't been another way?
...reality of a hollow lens has the potential to
revolutionize education by bringing three-D content into the real-world.
Now ...biggest challenges for students learning anatomy is understanding the
body in three-dimensions and all the different systems fit together
using hologram as we can easily separate and focus in
on individual systems.
For example, we can focus in on the femur and
students can immediately see some of the types of fractures they may one day encounter in the clinic.
...I can leverage all these new capabilities or maintaining the important connection
with my students were both wearing a hollow ...I can see what
they're looking at what they're interacting with I can assess their progress
and they communicate with me and each other naturally, for example,
I can see if michelle has a question in class ...gwen has a question while learning remotely.
Now obviously
cadaver doesn't move this makes it difficult to see the way living body actually works.
All and doesn't have this limitation systems can be animated
easily see how things function?
Let's take a look at the center of the cardiovascular system the heart
...organ reality it's about the size of your face.
With ...length we can easily scale-up the hard ...students you
...new details.
We can even see inside the hard to see the valves and action.
This is a new way of seeing things ...it has the potential
help students understand the structure and physiology of the body in a way that's just not possible.
And, what you've just seen is a vision of ...could enhance one single
subject but as an educator it's easy for
me to see that it's not just anatomy that could benefit from this
technology this could change how everyone learns?
Imagine for a moment some of the other fields that could be changed.
For example, chemistry and genetics.
In paleontology.
And, the best part is we get to help ...
...future together I can't wait to see what you future holographic developers
are going to do with this amazing technology thanks thank you ...thank you michelle.
And, thank you to our friends at case western
and the cleveland clinic from nasa GPL.
To trimble.
To case western these are just a few of the amazing partners we
are actively collaborating with ...different industries now ...hologram
have become part of our everyday life.
Now I feel very fortunate to be in this moment in time all
the different pieces are starting to fall into place.
As we entered this decade the amount of processing our you can get into a
small form factor for a reasonable price point is just
staggering even in the last few years as we ...lands the
innovation in optics sensors and silicon has allowed us to move
forward a few orders of magnitude now people used to say
computers today can do enough my abstract just fine the internet
...just fine we going to do with all
of this extra computing our and the answer to that is that
...are going to put a different emphasis on it you workloads focus on
solving brand new problems in other words we are going to start using all
of this our specifically to help us understand humans
and the world around us so how do you do this.
With no wires with.
No, markers no external cameras with no phones
and no connection to a pc required ...to learn a little bit more
about this amazing magical device that is microsoft hollow lengths.
The hardware allows us to take these visions these ideas about
these new products and make it all real imagine a computer that allows
you put your
images anywhere and you can interact with things as a combination of the real-world and ...
...you have a bunch of different systems that need to come together in one big symphony.
...easy-to-understand is like ...onion the sudden another layer things which you
...only have caused a figure that out now we don't have room for error we don't have room for
...you don't have room for those normal things that happen
...just working with these people across the world
...very old together and to this brand new product.
We envision an all-in-one device ...was
built in batteries hands-free and, ...or the you have to come up with holographic
processing unit because you're constantly producing data every single millisecond
...successful complex ...very simple
...pure to accommodate so many requirements ...
progressive conference the audio components me to take in all of that information about ...my head where am
I looking so that your brain knows that there's something real over there enclosure rocks around
their users and ...distribution we have
so many sensors on this product to read all those in real-time and to do that in a very
powerful ...requires ...our of what they developed with the new version of windows we need to get the
hardware just right so that we can sort of understand creativity and the worlds.
I think we have great ideas of things ...get out of developers
...hundreds are great ideas and that's what bill ...all about I ...
...get out to people show them hey this is real and this actually works now if you ...
...with that.
With windows ...hologram ...
our universal windows apps and the ball universal windows apps can be
made to work on windows holographic everything you have seen
here today is a universal windows app developers this.
Opens up ...you've been of innovation any new vein of opportunity with
...you have ...new canvas to express
...creativity your apps can come to life and they can
be experience naturally in the world around you but scene
is believing so let's take a look at how portability
of experiences enabled by windows ten can change the way
makers like you interact with the physical things that you
built in to show us mixing hologram with io tea.
Please help me welcome onstage my very good friend nicole.
I'd likely that may be fifteen this year millions of people we use maker
kids like this one to enter robot
competitions and learn about electronics many of them we use raspberry pi
...which now supports windows ten
...core we were inspired to see what we could do with the
same hardware and hollow length so let me show you the fifteen wake up.
...out to the real be fifteen.
Because everyone ...ten device has API for human
an environment understanding we were able to overlay a
holographic robot on top of a physical one and one thing we notice all working
is you need your data to be easily accessible but adding
displays of this frame increases your cost and there's no way to see all that information
at once so let me show you how we check on our data we fifteen control panel.
This spatial your eyes system as a universal windows app.
I'm pulling the data from ...fifteen making as big as I needed to be
...placing awards relevant and my world and I love it ...nicole
...have to actually go back to her desk to do it this is a great example of
how windows stand mixer digital life more powerful by connecting
at with your real-life that's freight you can waste a lot of
time tweaking variables on another device before you test?
But, ...all I need to do is something simple like
change lady color I can use a control scheme.
Like this.
So, that's how we envision controls and displays evolving
great hologram now so many industrial robots ...paths.
Safely through their work ...let's take a look at how many go
...be ...navigate and how ...can help so
be fifteen sensors aren't created detecting obstacles but the cool thing is they don't
have to be my hollow lens can communicate that information
...fifteen half fighting ...
...now with windows ...we can scan an environment we can
cue up movement tasks and visualize the robots bath?
So, all I have to do is air ...the ground my hollow
...interprets the three-D points and tells be fifteen when to turn and
went to move forward now this is a great example of how portable
our windows experiences can be fifteen
...half to, you know, it's environment the room understanding
comes from windows holographic but what happens
when the environment actually changes that's no problem because ...morning hall
...I'm always aware of the fifteen I can see it updated its route to
go around you and this is critical if you're working with bigger robots like those
...automotive manufacturing you need to always be aware of a robots intentions
...lens helps developers understand robots better at any scale or
in any scenario this is just amazing thank you so much vehicle and nice to be
...be fifteen, fifteen say goodbye.
Now at some point in time you get this feeling you could actually be
creating something meaningful but that feeling is
materially different from seeing architects excited about it from
seen doctors in professors excited about it for ...
developers like you excited about it people outside of microsoft
...start understanding the tools.
...start understanding what they have in front of them who start painting with
these brain you ...and these brand new paint brushes.
It's humbling and it's exciting at the same time.
It is in that spirit that we have brought hundreds of hollow
lens devices.
Just like the ones you saw on stage today
at all running on windows stand so that you hear and
build ...experience hologram for yourselves over the next few days.
From holographic presentations featuring sky.
To one-on-one demos like the trimble
experience I showed you earlier today.
And, my personal favorite our very own holographic academy
where you'll be able to build your very first holographic experience
from scratch we have all lost to share with you this week here at
built now registration for
all of this begins after the keynote space
is limited so make sure you sign up for all of these activities by going
to the web or simply by using the build-up.
The holographic journey starts with you the windows developer's ...
...right here and it starts right now and with that I want
to thank you and let's welcome scott, yeah, back when stage thank you.
Thank you alex that's just magical staff.
Hopefully you get the essence of our ambition with windows
can when we say we want to move the users of windows to
move from needing windows choosing windows
to loving windows at the core of our company
is empowerment empowering us fall it's our mission
to empower every person in every organization on the
planet to achieve more and it starts by empowering every one of
you every developer on the planet thank you so very much for
being here today and ...at this conference I thought we will
and today's morning keynote by playing the music that david
compose for us this morning on staff bad thank you and have a great